Kevin Andres



Software Engineer

Software engineer with 5+ years of enterprise experience in full-stack development, mainly using Java/Kotlin/Node and React while participating in the complete product development lifecycle. Specializing in backend development and micro-services architecture on cloud services.

Animated by well-designed code and discovering new business problematics; Interested in SaaS, WebApplication, Blockchain, Decentralized Applications and Finance.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Engineer Mar 2022 - Present

RCT.ai - AI & Blockchain industry

Beijing - China

Working on Delysium, first cross-chain AAA game, as the InfraLead for the web3 team. Interacting weekly with stakeholders and PMs; while developing the core web3 modules deployed on AWS with Kubernetes.

- Lead ImmutableX chain integration and chain syncer development on NodeJs
- Lead Delysium SSO on NodeJs: web3 & social auth, whitelist, micro-services API keys, Redis
- Infrastructure engineering of a decentralized game publishing model (DMO) including protocol token, staking, player incentives and game Multiverse; orchestrated into smart-contracts and micro-services.
- Develop cross-chain NFT state listener for in-game integration using Kafka event streams
- Tokens & NFT cross-chain products: marketplace, airdrop & batch transfer, metadata manager
- Smart-contract development on Ethereum and Polygon chains; testing and auditing

Software Engineer Backend

Jun 2020 - Mar 2022

Stey - Lodging industry

Beijing - China

Backend development of 20+ micro-services in Kotlin and Scala. Architecture based on Azure cloud, Azure CI, Kubernetes, SpringCloud and event streams with Kafka.

- Design Housekeep management system using Akka & Kafka event streams
- Tencent SMS & Chat API integration
- IOT third-parties APIs integration for connected rooms
- Implement digital Invoices & Contracts
 - Mobile payment using WeChat & Alipay APIs; transactions tracking and reporting
 - Legal E-Signing; Automatic Billing; IOT locker; PDF generation
 - Kotlin first PDF generation library with generic grid structure, using PDFBox

Full-Stack Engineer Nov 2018 - Jan 2020

Scottish Power - Energy industry

Glasgow - Scotland

- Develop webapp in React which displays electricity data and blackouts across the UK
- Supervision and mentoring of an intern on the development of chatbots on NodeJs with IBM Watson
- Responsible for designing and developing a complete Push-Notification management service
 - RestAPI (Spring) push notifications based on events triggered by third party services
 - Webapp (React) with Kerberos login to administrate notification streams and display data reports
 - Successfully designed and deployed v1 to production on JBoss with APIs behind WSO2

Software Developer

Jan 2018 - Sep 2018

Linnworks - E-commerce industry

Portsmouth - England

Develop features to tackle e-commerce & warehouse problematics.

- Create webapps using .Net & Angular for warehouse management
- C# macro on AWS using linnworks SDKs to expand the core-product's functionalities
- Shipping integration of Global-E using their third-party APIs

EDUCATION

Epitech - European Institute of Information Technology

Jul 2012 - Mar 2018

Master Information Technology

Paris

Beijing Jiaotong University

Sep 2016 - Jun 2017

Master Software Engineering

Beijing

SKILLS LIST

French native; English professional; Chinese beginner

- Language: Java, Kotlin, Typescript & JavaScript, Solidity, Scala, C++, Go
- Back-End: RestAPI, Micro-services, Blockchain, Smart-contracts, Spring Boot/Cloud/Security, Express, Redis, Akka, Kafka, Lagom, Zipkin, Swagger, JUnit, Mockito
- Front-End: ReactJs, Web3
- DB: SQL, MongoDB, Elastic Search, Exposed, Hibernate & JPA, Slick, Mybatis
- Tools: NodeJs, Etherum, IMX, Hardhat & Truffle, Kubernetes, Git, Nginx, AWS, Azure, Docker